<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on 📝 bledleys blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on 📝 bledleys blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 12:36:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trying out the Zed editor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-27-testing-out-zed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 12:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-27-testing-out-zed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-zed-editor&#34;&gt;What is Zed editor?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Zed&lt;/a&gt; is a fairly new code or text editor on the block. Cool name right?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s written in &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt; and claims to be fast and light with an emphasis on using AI and collaborative features.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be straight with you though - I have no interest in the AI features or collaboration tools. I&amp;rsquo;m not a programmer, I just tinker around with my computers configuration files and theming etc and work on some basic code for my website. I usually use Emacs or Neovim for that purpose.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Why would you want to try it?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I kind of believe that you should have a terminal based and a GUI based solution for doing the same tasks on your system. I recently moved to the Gnome desktop environment and there&amp;rsquo;s a kind of polish and unified look to that which has led to me investigating more GUI based solutions that fit nicely into my system. My first though on seeing Zed was - that looks pretty, let&amp;rsquo;s give it a spin as my default text editor&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-install-zed&#34;&gt;How to install Zed&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Linux version only came out a couple of months ago, you can get in MacOS but Windows users will have to wait.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On Arch Linux you can find Zed in the main repositories. See their &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for alternative installation methods.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#e5e5e5;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo pacman -S zed&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-launch&#34;&gt;First launch&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can launch zed in the way you usually launch programs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On first launch you will see a little pop up that asks for a few default options. You can opt in or out of telemetry, set a theme and change your base keymap type here. You can also enable Vim mode here or set it later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Enable cli&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One of the first things you may want to do it is enable cli access so you can launch the editor in the terminal. You can do this in the graphical menu or through the control panel searching for cli::install&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Accessing the Control pallette&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The idea of a control or command pallette will be familiar to some from other programs and can be activated with Ctrl+Shift+p.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;So now in the terminal you will be able to type&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#e5e5e5;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;zeditor ~/myproject&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;to open a directory as a project&#xA;or&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
